Inventory of the Davison Art Center Exhibition Catalogs Collection, 1958 - 1999
Davison Art Center Exhibition Catalogs Collection, 1958 - 1999
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Davison Art Center.
1000-21
2.0
4
The Davison Art Center, housed in the 1839 Alsop House, comprises exhibition galleries, classrooms, offices, and the university’s collection of prints and photographs. The Art Center and much of its collection was the gift of George W. (Wesleyan class of 1892) and Harriet Baldwin Davison.
This collection includes catalogs to Davison Art Center exhibitions and a collection of exhibition announcements in the form of cards, postcards, and brochures.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Acquired by Olin Library.
Historical Note
The Davison Art Center, housed in the 1839 Alsop House, comprises exhibition galleries, classrooms, offices, and the university’s collection of prints and photographs. The building was acquired by Wesleyan in 1949 and has been used by the university as the Davison Art Center since 1952.
A gift from George W. Davison ’1892 allowed the building’s renovation to take place. Davison, a book and print collector, began giving parts of his collection of prints to the university in 1937. The original collection was housed in the Davison Art Rooms in Olin Library before forming the core collection of the Davison Art Center. After Davison’s death in 1953, Wesleyan has continued to add to its holdings of prints and has included photography as an additional collecting focus.
Collection Overview
This collection includes catalogs to Davison Art Center exhibitions and a collection of exhibition announcements in the form of cards, postcards, and brochures.
Collection Arrangement
Arrangement is chronological by date of exhibition.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Exhibition announcements and postcards, 1961-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition announcements and postcards, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition announcements and postcards, 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition announcements and postcards, 1986-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition announcements and postcards, 2001-[ongoing] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The George W. and Harriet B. Davison Art Center. 1952 (soft and hardcover copies).
    - Masterpieces from the Wesleyan Print Collection. Commencement 1952.
    - Mannerist Drawings, Prints and Paintings. January 14 to February 7, 1957.
  - 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ukiyo-e. January 10-31, 1960.
    - Modern Collegiate Architecture USA. March 8-19, 1961.
    - The City and the Land. October 20 – November 9, 1961.
    - Ralston Crawford. December 5-27, 1961.
    - Prints from the Davison Art Center Collection. 1962.
    - William Hogarth, Pictorial Dramatist. November 11 – December 30, 1962.
    - The New Art. March 1-22, 1964.
    - Oskar Kokoschka: Paintings, Drawings, Lithographs. April 1-23, 1964.
    - Paintings, Drawings and Prints from the Collection of LeRoy P. Ward. November 12 – December 6, 1964.
    - Henry Moore. 1965 exhibition of Art & Idea. May 14 – June 8, 1965.
    - Honore Daumier. Drawings, Lithographs, Sculptures, Books. Autumn 1965.
    - Reconstructions by Norman Ives. September 23 – October 13, 1965.
    - Harry Nadler ’65. November 13 – December 3, 1965.
    - Robert Vickery. October 26 - November 20, 1966.
  - 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - List of Davison Art Center Exhibitions for 1966-1967.
    - Ilse Getz. February 1 – 23, 1967.
    - Samuel M. Green. February 27 – March 18, 1967.
    - The Butterfield Years. June, 1967.
    - Commencement Exhibitions. 1967.
    - Around the Automobile. February 12 – March 5, 1968.
    - The New Chinese Landscape. April, 1968.
    - Paintings by Luigi Biolghini. December 27, 1968 – January 6, 1969.
    - Portfolios by Richard Upton. March 7-31, 1969.
    - Works from the Collection of James Lord. September 17 – October 6, 1969.
    - Italian Master Drawings from the Collecton of Janos Scholz. November 20, 1969.
  - 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Hnizdovsky: Twenty-seven Woodcuts. January 29 – February 15, 1970.
    - Calotypes by David Octavius Hill and Robert Adamson. January 30 – February 15, 1970.
    - Recent Acquisitions of the Davison Art Center Collection. January 15 – February 7, 1971.
    - Lorenzo Homar: Graphics. October 8-31, 1971.
    - Five Sets by Five Artists. November 1-30, 1971.
  - 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Early Lithography, 1801-1835. February 22, 1972.
      2 copies.
    - Davison Art Center Selected Acquisitions 1955-1972. April – May 1972.
    - The Prints of Richard Hamilton. September 28 – November 4, 1973.
    - Offset Lithography. November 9 – December 9, 1973.
  - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - The Fable of the Sick Lion: A Fifteenth-Century Blockbook. April 27 – June 9, 1974.
    - The Avant Garde in Theatre and Art: French Playbills of the 1890s. October 5 – November 3, 1974.
  - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2-2a)
    - Images of Death. January 25 – March 2, 1975.
    - Everything You Always Wanted to Know About Prints, But Were Afraid to Ask. March 2 – April 15, 1975.
    - Prints and Drawings by Gabriel de Saint-Aubin. March 7 – April 13, 1975.
    - Prints and Drawings by Lee Bontecou. May 2 – June 15, 1975.
    - Recent American Etching. October 10 – November 23, 1975.
    - Oscar Kokoschka: Literary and Graphic Works 1906-1923. November 1-December 21, 1975.
      Includes both Wesleyan catalog (2 copies) and travelling exhibition catalogs.
  - 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - André Kertész. January 23-February 20, 1976.
    - An Inventory of the Peter Boynton Collection of Scrimshaw and Other Artifacts. February 1976.
    - American Prints 1880-1945. March 10-April 11, 1976.
    - Prints, Bill Davison 1970-1976. [1976].
    - WPA/FAP Graphics [1976-1977].
    - Color and the Graphic Arts. September 11-October 6, 1977.
  - 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Fifteenth Century Woodcuts. January 20-February 19, 1978.
    - British Art from the Collection of Robert and Helen Mandelbaum. October 6-29, 1978.
    - American Photographs from the Collection of Russell G. D’Oench. November 3- 26, 1978.
    - Paper as Medium. [1978-1980].
    - Marine Prints by Phillip Kappel. January 19 - February 11, 1979.
    - Prints and Drawings by Joseph Pennell, 1860-1926. May 5 – June 3, 1979.
    - Prints, Drawings, Paintings: Philip Pearlstein. September 7 – October 7, 1979.
  - 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Prints of Armand Seguin 1869-1903. February 8 – March 14, 1980.
    - Pyramidal Influence in Art. Summer 1980.
    - Metropolis: Images of New York 1918-1938. September 5 – October 12, 1980.
    - Comedy and Revolution: Satire from Hogarth to Daumier. January 22 – February 15, 1981.
    - No Title: The Collection of Sol Lewitt. October 21 – December 20, 1981.
  - 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Drawings and Paintings from Wesleyan Collections. February 5 – March 12, 1982.
    - Masterpieces of Photography from Wesleyan and Private Collections. April 30 – June 15, 1982.
    - Three Scottish Printmakers: Cameron, Bone, and McBey. September 1 – October 13, 1982.
    - Portraits of Native Americans by W. Langdon Kihn, 1920-1937. January 26 – March 10, 1983.
    - A Cultivated Taste: Whistler and American Print Collectors. September 1 – October 24, 1983.
  - 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Chinese Revolutionary Woodcuts 1935-1948. January 26 – March 9, 1984.
    - More Vivid Places: Victorian Photographs of Britain, The Middle East, and Orient. August 29 – October 25, 1984.
    - Ming Tradeware Ceramics from a Philippine Collection. October 2 – 4, 1984.
  - 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Natural and Pastoral Themes by Barbizon Printmakers. January 23 – March 8, 1985.
    - Aspects of Sculpture: the Paul Magriel Collection. November 7 – December 15, 1985.
    - Jim Dine Prints 1977-1985. January 22 – March 9, 1986.
  - 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Robert F. Sheehan: Color Photography 1948-1958. 1987.
    - Collaboration Printmaking Today. March 25 – June 7, 1987.
    - Gian Domenico Tiepolo and the Flight into Egypt. January 26 - March 6, 1988.
    - Prints and Drawings from the Collection of Eileen and Gerald Burke. March 25 – May 8, 1988.
    - Alvin Lucier. November 2-23, 1988.
  - 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Destruction and Destiny. The Photographs of A. J. Russell: Directing American Energy in War and Peace, 1862-1869. January 15 – March 5, 1989.
    - Friends of the Davison Art Center Acquisitions 1962-1988. March 28 – June 4, 1989.
    - Second State. January 24 – March 9, 1990.
    - Jose Luis Cuebas: Homage to Quevedo. March 27 - June 10, 1990.
    - Luther Gregg Sullivan Drawings. May 15 – June 10, 1990.
    - Multiple Memories: Collaborations in American Printmaking. [1990].
  - 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Riding on a Blue Note, Vincent D. Smith. January 20 – March 10, 1991.
    - 'Husbands Always Make Me Laugh:' Wives, Paramours, and Bluestockings in the Prints of Daumier and Gavarni. May 3 – June 9, 1991.
    - Atget’s Churches. March 24 – June 7, 1992.
    - Thirty Years at Universal Limited Art Editions. September 2 – October 25, 1992.
    - Howardena Pindell: Paintings and Drawings 1972-1992. [1992].
  - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Sylvia Plimack Mangold: Works on Paper 1968-1991. April 6 – June 6, 1993.
    - Chiaroscuro 1500-1800. September 1 – October 20, 1993.
    - Constructing Modernism: Berenice Abbott/Henry-Russell Hitchcock. October 28 – December 10, 1993.
  - 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Block/Plate/Stone: What a Print Is. March 28 – June 4, 1995.
    - Prodigal Son Narratives 1480-1980. August 30 – October 20, 1995.
    - Jim Dine’s Raven on White Paper. March 26 – June 2, 1996.
    - Keiji Shinohara: Interpretations in Woodcut. August 28 – October 16, 1996.
  - 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Looking In: Photographs from the Collection of Andrew Szegedy-Maszak and Elizabeth Bobrick. January 21 – March 6, 1998.
    - Alice Burr – Photographer: A Californian Pictorialist Rediscovered. September 8 – October 16, 1998.
    - James McNeill Whistler & the Etching Revival. September 1 – October 17, 1999.